_Last updated: 03. June, 2022_

Privacy Policy
==============

_Note: Please be aware that only our Terms of Service and Privacy Policy in English are legally binding. While translations of these documents may be provided for your convenience, they are translated by the community and are thus not legal documents._

This Privacy Policy applies to the official instance of Revolt, available at revolt.chat. Self-hosted instances may choose to adopt this Privacy Policy if they wish.

### Introduction

We get that legal documents can be overwhelming and boring, so we've tried our best to keep it as simple and possible while providing the information needed. It is important however to remember that these terms are legally binding between yourself and us if you choose to use Revolt, so please read them carefully before proceeding - We will continue to improve and tackle some sections.

### Your Privacy

Your privacy is very important to us, and we will ensure protecting your privacy when using our services.

**Revolt** is an open-source project (source code is available on our [GitLab](https://gitlab.insrt.uk/revolt)), and we respect our user's privacy while remaining transparent with our users. We only collect limited data from our users that is absolutely necessary.

* **Account Information**: We collect data from our users when they register for an account on Revolt, such as: the registered e-mail address, hashed password, and chosen username.
* **Servers and Groups**: If you create or join a group/server on Revolt, we collect and store the names of the group/server to provide the service.
* **Self-hosted instances**: Since self-hosted instances aren't operated by us, we cannot enforce our own Privacy Policy, Acceptable Usage Policy or Terms of Service there. Please visit self-hosted instances at your own discretion.

### Who is this information shared with?

We will NEVER sell your data to any third-parties, although we use certain service providers to process your data, such as:

* [Hetzner](https://hetzner.com/), provides us with cloud services to run the Revolt backend and database.
* [Vercel](https://vercel.com/), provides us with cloud services to deploy and run parts of the Revolt frontend. No actual personal information or data is shared with Vercel.
* [Scaleway](https://www.scaleway.com/en/), provides us with cloud servers used to host our voice channels. Voice information is processed on their cloud servers but no actual personal information or data is shared with Scaleway.
* [hCaptcha](https://hcaptcha.com/), provides us with the tools necessary to stop abuse of our platform. [See footnote.](#hcaptcha)
* [Cloudflare](https://cloudflare.com/), provides us with DDoS mitigation and content delivery acceleration.

_Law & Order: We may disclose your information to third parties only if such disclosure is absolutely necessary to comply with a valid legal process, protect any person from death or serious injury, prevent fraud or abuse, or protect our rights, property, safety and interest_.

### Where is my information stored?

Since this is an open-source project, we have team members across Europe and North America. Your information is currently stored on first-party servers in Germany and your media is stored on first-party servers in Lithuania.

If you wish to request deletion of any information stored on our servers, including any requests under GDPR or DMCA, please contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://revolt.chat/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

_Exceptions to third-parties service providers which is used to process your data as mentioned above._

### Our commitment to children's privacy

We follow [The Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (“COPPA”)](https://www.ftc.gov/enforcement/rules/rulemaking-regulatory-reform-proceedings/childrens-online-privacy-protection-rule), which requires online service providers to obtain parental consent before they knowingly collect personally identifiable information online from children who are under 13 years of age. This applies to every user of our platform, regardless of different consent laws in different countries. We do not knowingly collect or solicit personally identifiable information from children under 13 years of age. If we learn we have collected personal information from a child under 13 years of age, we will immediately delete that information from our servers. If you are a parent or guardian of a child under the age of 13 and believe that they have disclosed personal information to us, please contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://revolt.chat/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

### Changes to our Privacy Policy

As we keep improving our services, we may update our Privacy Policy in the future if needed. We will notify you of any changes made to our Privacy Policy by specifying the date.

You are advised to review our Privacy Policy periodically for any changes. Such changes to our Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.

### Contact Us

Feel free to contact us if you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy or any of the above statements. You may contact us by emailing [\[email protected\]](https://revolt.chat/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

### hCaptcha

> This section has been adapted from hCaptcha's documentation.

We use the hCaptcha anti-bot service (hereinafter "hCaptcha") on our website. This service is provided by Intuition Machines, Inc., a Delaware US Corporation ("IMI"). hCaptcha is used to check whether the data entered on our website (such as on a login page or contact form) has been entered by a human or by an automated program. To do this, hCaptcha analyzes the behavior of the website or mobile app visitor based on various characteristics. This analysis starts automatically as soon as the website or mobile app visitor enters a part of the website or app with hCaptcha enabled.

When using the [Revolt App](https://app.revolt.chat/), hCaptcha will only begin analysis when you:

* Submit a login request.
* Submit a registration request.
* Submit a password reset / email resend request.

For the analysis, hCaptcha evaluates various information (e.g. IP address, how long the visitor has been on the website or app, or mouse movements made by the user). The data collected during the analysis will be forwarded to IMI.

Data processing is based on Art. 6(1)(f) of the GDPR (DSGVO): the website or mobile app operator has a legitimate interest in protecting its site from abusive automated crawling and spam. IMI acts as a "data processor" acting on behalf of its customers as defined under the GDPR, and a "service provider" for the purposes of the California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA). For more information about hCaptcha and IMI's privacy policy and terms of use, please visit the following links: [https://hcaptcha.com/privacy/](https://hcaptcha.com/privacy/) and [https://hcaptcha.com/terms](https://hcaptcha.com/terms).

#### App

#### Developers

#### Team

#### Legal

#### Subscribe
